It's a good idea to rest. It's time
to take responsibility for your actions.
You're no different
to the gods that rule us.
You created life
and left your children to their fate.
Who made you judge?
Who do you think you are?
No! No, no, no... Oropo!
Yugo!
Yoo-hoo! Yugo!
-Not you again.
-Still us. Always us, Yugo!
You know we're part of you.
There's no way to get rid of us.
Why would you want him
to get rid of us, Qilby?
-We're his best friends!
-Go away!
Isn't that right, Yugo?
Leave me alone!
Yes! We are one!
I wasn't expecting it to be this easy.
Tell me it isn't true.
You haven't been lying all this time?
Adamai, grow up already.
I did manipulate you all a little,
but it was necessary.
We'll change the rules
that govern the universe,
I couldn't waste time convincing you.
But you told me everything.
Yes, there were a few of you
I could really count on.
You have loved me sincerely for so long.
You've always supported me.
I wish I could give you
what you've given me...
But I can't give you what you want.
Now that I'm whole again, I owe it
to myself to be honest with you
I promise I won't lie to you anymore.
Let me go! You're no better
than the other lunatics we've fought.
Don't say that, Amalia,
I'm the one you love.
I am Yugo.
I should have seen it before.
You're nothing like Yugo.
He doesn't lie or take advantage
of family and friends.
You lied to Adamai to turn him against us.
You played with your friends' feelings
to get what you want.
It's true. What nasty trick did you play
on them? What did you promise them?
You're not Yugo. No matter what you do,
you never will be.
Amalia, you'll come to realize
that the work I do is for the good.
You're all too young to understand
what I'm trying to do.
You simply need to trust me.
Trust you?
Trust you? Really?
Dame Echo, no!
Stay back, girls.
You're the only person I trusted.
I followed you for centuries.
I believed in your cause.
But the worst part is,
I thought you loved me...
Like all your children here,
they all trusted you.
They all believed you loved them,
but, actually, you were just using us.
No, Echo...
Now I understand.
We were never more to you
than a substitute family.
You wanted to be in
the Brotherhood of the Tofu.
You dreamt of being with her.
You're right, Princess Amalia.
Oropo is a monster, a heartless freak.
That's enough, Echo. You've gone too far.
All of you... You...
You're not the first and you know it.
Oropo has recruited
hundreds of demigods...
and never hesitated to sacrifice them
for his cause.
I said that was enough, Echo!
-Have you forgotten how to obey?
-Do it, my love.
Strike and release me already.
Echo is right. I took advantage
of you all. That's a fact.
What kind of supreme god would I be
if I couldn't face my own flaws?
A supreme god?
I think I've heard enough.
Ah, Goultard. A good example
of the futility of the gods.
All of you!
I did it for your own good.
To build a better world.
You mean all this time, you were using us?
You've treated us like trash.
I know what you made me do, Oropo.
You used me when I was lost.
You made me use Ogrest,
so he'd unleash his sadness on the world.
You... You're responsible for Ogrest's
chaos and the resulting deaths?
A necessary evil.
Just like you gave the Eliacube
to Noximilian the Clockmaker.
A necessary evil
to weaken those ruling us.
I can't believe it.
I understand it's a lot for you all
to take in.
You are a monster!
Amalia, no!
Amalia!
♪ Where is Yugo today
Can he come out to play? ♪
♪ Where is Yugo today?
♪ There he is ♪
♪ Run and play ♪
I beat you once...
I'll do it again.
He's distracted.
Rubilax, can you hear what I'm thinking?
There's usually nothing up there,
so even the smallest thought echoes.
Okay, let's go!
You're quite the fighter, Yugo.
You hit your brother now?
And them? Are you going to hit them, too?
You were supposed to come to us.
Take care of us.
-You were supposed to rule us.
-Find us a home.
You didn't have time to look, right Yugo?
I'll make it right. I promise!
I... I wasn't ready.
That should keep you quite busy.
It will all be over very soon.
When the Eliacube is ready...
I'll send it into Ingloriom.
That will be the end of the gods.
I am a fool!
How could I have been so stupid?
And when that's done, you'll join me.
The first Dofus has been absorbed.
It will go very quickly now.
Here we go, finally.
What made you change your mind?
Oropo activated the Hyperzaap.
It's time to join the others.
Arpagone, darling...
I know I wasn't always
a good husband, but...
You should know I've always loved you.
Things are heating up.
Can I help Papa? Pretty please?
Say yes! Please, please, please!
We'll go together.
Your father's having all the fun!
In your condition? With the baby?
That's a bad idea, Eva.
We've been away from Dally for too long.
We must help him.
Anyway, I don't think
we're safe here anymore.
Exactly!
What a family of tough guys.
You're jealous
there's more Iop than Cra in it.
And he hits hard! Let's get going!
I need you to keep them away.
I still have to finish off Dally.
There's no point
in making them watch that.
And if you use force,
be careful not to hurt the baby.
If I can't convince Flopin and Elely
to join us,
I can always raise him
to meet our needs perfectly.
Don't worry, Amalia. It'll be fine.
We've seen worse.
No, you don't understand.
I really can't let you guys out.
It's much too dangerous!
I'm sorry. I was just following orders
given to me.
Sipho!
You've got two seconds to...
Give our baby brother back!
You make a cute couple.
Shut up, Rubi!
Don't you see we need encouragement?
Nonsense! You're only good when
the going's tough. You're lousy otherwise.
He's got a point.
The two of you together
are half as clever as me.
It's not that complicated.
You add your smarts to mine.
Then divide that by two,
carry the three and... I'll start over!
Never mind. Math's not your strong suit.
Get that nut-job and make him suffer.
You trained your Shushu well.
He speaks Iop good now.
-It took long enough.
-Less talking, more action!
So, Dally, how about this?
I take care of Oropo
and you free the others?
I have a better idea.
I really fell for that.
Brother... I am so sorry.
Me, too, Yugo.
Sorry that you never keep your promises.
How long do you want me
to wait for you, Yugo?
The years are slipping away.
You have an eternity to decide.
I'm sorry, Amalia.
Dally, stop, I am your friend.
My friend is Yugo!
You're just another nut-job in our way.
When we're done with you, we'll move on!
But I am Yugo, you idiot!
Can't any of you understand that?
Well, you know, I am an Iop.
We're not so good at understanding.
From this point on,
I will destroy anyone...
...who doesn't accept me.
Dally!
Still there, Yugo?
Why are you still fighting,
lost in the depths of my mind?
Stop struggling. Become part of me.
-It would be so much easier.
-I'm not going to let myself die.
Die?
You know you cannot die.
You come back to life all the time.
Not to mention the dragon blood in
your veins that makes you age very slowly.
Aren't you tired of all that?
Don't you want to pass the baton?
I am you, Yugo,
and I know what you've been going through.
More than anyone, I know the weight
on your shoulders.
Let me govern the Eliatropes.
Let me help the world, Yugo.
I can't believe that I'd ever...
...be like you!
Think, Yugo, before it's too late.
There's no way I'd ever be like you!